Joshua Kennedy

Professional Tinkerer Resides in Scotland





Experience

Cloud Automation Engineer

NatWest - Since September 2021

- Joined a small R&D team with the purpose of expanding the banks onprem cloud computing capabilities. Honed skills in Openshift, Kubernetes and general container orchestration.
- vault / venafi integrations
- Cloud Paks

Middleware Systems Engineer

NatWest - February 2019 - September 2021

- Built automation to streamline common support tasks for deployment orchestration tooling with a colleague. One of the tasks automated was agent upgrading. This facilitated the upgrade of over 1600 agents in the span of 6 months across 50 different teams.
- Provided support for both users and administrators of the new deployment orchestration tooling. I created a large amount of documentation and hosted workshops. This resulted in the upskilling of an entire support team in the administration of the tooling.

Middleware Technical Analyst

NatWest - January 2018 - February 2019

- Delivered technical support for Java based enterprise software, providing successful resolution for over 150 individual incidents.
- Developed infrastructure support scripts for and assisted in standing up deployment orchestration tooling. Through this I developed new skills in RESTful API interaction and high availability clustering technologies.

WebSphere Technical Apprentice

NatWest - January 2016 - January 2018

- Developed knowledge on KornShell scripting and used it to automate a manual licensing process for ~5000 servers.
- Audited and improved a certificate renewal tracking workflow. Picking up skills in Visual Basic and SQL along the way.



Education and Certification

Red Hat Certified Specialist in Containers and Kubernetes July 2022

Proficiency in podman, kubernetes & OpenShift

IT & Telecoms Professional January 2017 - January 2018 SCQF Level 8, QA Apprenticeship

IT & Telecoms Professional January 2016 - January 2017 SCQF Level 6, QA Apprenticeship

Personal Projects

Stateful

C / Javascript

A Pebble watchapp designed to control RESTful API's with minimal clicks

MPRIS Panel

Javascript / DBus

A media controller for linux that uses a 'smart-switching' technique to effortlessly control multiple media sources.

Snowdon II WiFi

C / Assembly

A hardware mod for the Snowdon II soundbar. Implements a HTTP server and infrared NEC encoder from scratch to enable IR remote code signalling over

About me

An inquisitive learner with a vested interest in technology. Will ask questions and push knowledge boundaries to get the job done. Six years of prior experience in an engineering setting with exposure to multiple scripting and programming languages. All underpinned by a keen sense for problem solving. An inquisitive learner with a vested interest in technology. Will ask questions and push knowledge boundaries to get the job done. Six years of prior experience in an engineering setting with exposure to multiple scripting and programming languages. All underpinned by a keen sense for problem solving. An inquisitive learner with a vested interest in technology. Will ask questions and push knowledge boundaries to get the job done. Six years of prior experience in an engineering setting with exposure to multiple scripting and programming languages. All underpinned by a keen sense for problem solving. An inquisitive learner with a vested interest in technology. Will ask questions and push knowledge boundaries to get the job done. Six years of prior experience in an engineering setting with exposure to multiple scripting and programming languages. All underpinned by a keen sense for problem solving.

Skills



Python **JavaScript**

Hardware Hacking

Contact



kennedn.com

in kennedn kennedn

